# Shubham Arjun Singh

## Personal info



Date of birth: 17/07/1992 **Nationality:** Indian

Flat No 203, HV Homes, JCR Layout, Panathur, Bangalore Address:

560103, India

Phone number: 9795177019

**Email address:** shubhamarjunsingh@gmail.com

**Total Experience:** 5.5 Years

**Designation:** SOFTWARE ENGINEER (Full Stack Developer)

## Profile

Experienced Full Stack Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the IT industry. Skilled in Java 8, Spring, Restful Webservices, Angular 2+, Javascript, CSS, HTML and SQL, NoSQL, Cloud. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.) focused in Computer Science from Madan Mohan Malaviya University of Technology Gorakhpur.

# 

#### **Technologies/Languages**

Core Java/J2EE Java Script, JQuery JSP,CSS Spring 4.0, REST Webservices **SQL,Stored Procedures** Jenkins, SVN, GIT Apache Tomcat 8.5, UNIX Maven, Ant, TFS, Build Forge Data Structures, Algorithms

### **Frameworks**

Spring MVC Spring Boot, Struts 2.5 Angular 2+

#### **Cloud Tools:**

Docker, Kubernetes, Spinnaker, Rancher, Azure, AWS, No SOL

0000

10/2020 - present

#### **Database**

Microsoft SQL Server **Oracle SQL Developer** 



# Work experience

**Deloitte USI** Bangalore India

**Full Stack Developer Project Description:** 

Koop is a routing application that is basically being used for the routing of the ecommerce orders to a Kroger store or and Ocado fulfillment centers. It takes the created order schema and do manipulation over the schema according to the routing source and then publish the messages to the message queue with the order details, also it consumes the messages from both the sources and make the schema changes accordingly.

#### **Contribution:**

- · Working in an agile delivery team.
- · Involved in requirements gathering from onsite team.
- · Analyzed the requirements and provided hours of estimation
- · Involved in analysis and end-to-end development of functionality.
- · Implementing business logic using java, J2EE.
- · Working on the front-end using Anguler2+.
- Taken the responsibility to automate the continuous delivery of the application.
- Involved in Bug fixing for each spring releases and delivering the fixes on time.
- · Writing Junit test cases using Mockito.



CGI Bangalore

India

Full Stack Developer Project Description:

10/2018 -10/2020

POL DEV is a Payroll Support application which provides the calculation of salary based on the working day, Leaves taken and hours worked on daily basis. It calculates the salary based on the different scenario and conditions and generates the final salary.

Software Engineer Analyst Project Description:

03/2016 - 10/2018

Accenture Bangalore India

Enterprise Product Document generator is a document generating application. It is capable of providing various type of documents and these documents are useful for availing a health plan. It has the basic functionalities like Create, Clone, View, search and downloading PDF and word documents. Every document is communicated in JSON format between server and the application. The main purpose of this application is to generate the product documents. Documents can be generated in either word/PDF format. Cloning, Mass updates, Mass Publish, Reports are some of the important functionalities. It is an end to end application for document processing.

# Education

MMMUT, Gorakhpur Gorakhpur India **B.Tech in CSE** 

05/2012 - 06/2015

Governmet Polytechnic Gorakhpur Gorakhpur India **Diploma** 

05/2009 - 05/2012

SDIC, Deoria Deoria India 12th

05/2008 - 05/2009